ynhh.org 2005-04-03

# Privacy Policy - Yale-New Haven Hospital

**Page Contents**  
  
Personal information  
gathered  
  
Your control  
  
Security   
  
Children  
  
Outside resources  
  
Questions?   

**Site Contents**  

**Phone Numbers**  
  
Directory assistance  
**(203) 688-4242**  
  
Patient information  
**(203) 688-4177**  
  
Adult emergency  
**(203) 688-2222**  
  
Children's emergency  
**(203) 688-3333**  
  
Admitting  
**(203) 688-2221**  
  
Children's admitting  
**(203) 688-3331**  
  
Psychiatric admitting  
**(203) 688-9907**  

**Mailing address:**  
  
Yale-New Haven Hospital  
20 York Street  
New Haven, CT  
06510-3202  
|  | 

###  **Our policies regarding your privacy**

Yale-New Haven Hospital is dedicated to providing you with health care, information and referral services of the highest quality, while at the same time protecting your privacy.

We insist that our staff observe patient confidentiality—respecting your right to privacy about your medical records and experience with this hospital. 

  * Notice of Privacy Policy, Yale-New Haven Hospital (pdf file, 94.2 KB)  
_Note:_ You will need [Adobe Acrobat Reader](http://www.adobe.com/prodindex/acrobat/readstep.html "Adobe Acrobat Free Reader") installed in order to read the pdf file. 

**Web Site Privacy Policy**  
While you may be asked to provide personal data in using this Web site, we can assure you this information will be treated with the same care we treat all patient information. Any data we collect about you will be used only to help us develop customized programs and services suited to your needs and interests. 

We will not share your personal data with any party outside Yale-New Haven Hospital or Yale New Haven Health System. 

* * *

**What personal information do we gather from those who visit this site?**

| 1. |  **Information you have provided**  
We collect and store any information you enter on our Web site, or provide to us in offline contacts we have with you. Information is collected from visitors to the site in the following areas: 

We also collect information from those who fill out requests at booths or events sponsored by Yale-New Haven where we ask for permission to mail information about hospital services. In some cases, our communication may be by E-mail and utilizing the Web site.   
  
---|---  
  |    
2. | **Information gathered automatically**  
When you browse our Web site, you do so anonymously. We do log automatically your IP address (the Internet address of your computer), the Web pages you visit and the time of your visit, but we do not link this information to anything that could identify you personally. The only other type of information automatically provided to us is the type of computer and operating system you are using. Your browser supplies us with this information, which we use to improve the performance of our site. In aggregate, this information helps us understand how our site is being used and which parts of the site are of most interest to those who use it. Analysis of this information helps us to make continual improvements on the site. 

Some have expressed concerns about "cookies." In our Physician Referral Online feature, we make use of "cookies" to store the zip code you provide (as well as your name and address if you provide it) so we can customize subsequent screens for your use. For example, we use the information retained in the cookie to fill in the satisfaction survey screen for you if you provided information earlier in your session. If you return at a later date to this feature, you will not be required to re-enter information. If you have not asked for our involvement in obtaining a physician referral, then the only use we make of this information is to measure in the aggregate how many unique individuals are using this online service and what types of physicians are being sought. No individual identifications are made.   
  
  |    
3. | **Information from your E-mail communications with us**  
On every screen of our site, you have an opportunity to communicate with us by E-mail. E-mail contact is offered via:   
  
  |    
  |  **NOTE:**  
As you no doubt know, the security of E-mail communications on the Internet cannot be assured—although it is very likely to be secure. However, once your E-mail enters the Yale-New Haven Hospital system, it is protected by a firewall that ensures the security of the sensitive patient information contained in our electronic information systems.   
  
  | **Communications with the site editor**  
The information you provide is used to assist the editor in triaging your request to the most appropriate department. While retained in hard copy for our records, the information from this interaction (such as your name or E-mail address) will not be used in any way other than to address the specific request you have made and to monitor the quality of our interactions.  
---|---  
  |    
  | **Communications with the Yale-New Haven Health Call Center**  
The information you provide is used by the Call Center staff to respond to your inquiry—be it a request for a physician referral, a request for additional information or followup on a HealthLINK topic you have read about. The Call Center maintains strict confidentiality standards regarding the information consumers share with its staff in order to obtain appropriate medical care. Your interaction with the Call Center will be maintained in their system's electronic files. Because you have interacted with the Call Center previously, you may be contacted at a later date with additional information they believe may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to be contacted by the Call Center at a later date, [please let us know](mailto:prs@ynhh.org). 

If you are concerned about the security of your message before it reaches the hospital network, we invite you to instead call our referral coordinators:  |  Yale New Haven Health Call Center  
---  
(203) **688-2000** or toll free **888-700-6543**  
  
  |    
  | **Communications with "Ask the Expert"**  
Visitors to our "Ask the Expert" forums on breastfeeding and women's heart issues have the opportunity to post a message to the forums and receive a posted reply from either YNHH lactation specialists or nursing staff of our Call Center's nurse triage program. Your message is posted to the forum and the specialist/nurse is notified a new message is waiting there. You may sign your message (question or reply) with any name or initials you choose. We explain at the time you post your question or reply that we need your E-mail address in order to notify you of replies to your message. We may use your address to notify you of events or opportunities in which we think you might be interested. If you prefer that we not use and retain your address, leave the line blank and select "Do not send any replies." Your question or reply will still appear on the forum, but it will be up to you to check the forum for a response from our specialists/nurses.  
  |    
  | **Communications with our Patient Relations staff**  
Our site provides an E-mail link to our Patient Relations staff who will treat your communications with the same regard to your privacy we strive to employ in every patient interaction. If you are concerned about the security of your message before it reaches the hospital network, we invite you to instead call or write our Patient Relations staff:  
Patient Relations

Yale-New Haven Hospital  
20 York St.  
New Haven, CT 06510-3202  
(203) **688-3430**  
  
  |    
  | **All other contacts via the Web site with Yale-New Haven Hospital staff**  
The same assurances and cautions apply to any other contact with hospital staff via E-mail. If you are concerned about the security of the information in your E-mail message, a safer course would be to contact the person and request a telephone number or mailing address and use these for more sensitive communications.   

4. | **My Health Record**  
Yale-New Haven Hospital and other sites within Yale New Haven Health System offer an interactive health management tool we call "[My Health Record](https://yalenewhavenhealth.org/security/formslogin.asp?/MyPersonalHealth/EncryptDefault.asp?FROM=Personalization/)" (link opens new window). This tool was developed by [WellMed](http://www.wellmed.com/wellmed/) and licensed to us by [Healthvision](http://www.healthvision.com/). The tool offers risk assessments and gives the user the ability to maintain health records within their own personalized, password-secure areas. Personal information submitted within this area is maintained on WellMed computer systems. Yale-New Haven Hospital and Yale New Haven Health System do not have any access to your personal information, unless you choose for WellMed to share E-mail contact information with us. See the [privacy policy](http://www.healthvision.com/policies/priv_pol.htm) that is attached to My Health Record for further details.   
---|---  
  
* * *

**Your control of our communications with you** **  
** Yale-New Haven Hospital's goal is to serve you often as a trusted source of health information. To this end, we will make appropriate and reasonable use of the information collected through our various channels (Call Center, Web site, events, etc.) to continue to provide you with information you have indicated you have an interest in receiving. In marketing terms, this is called "opt-in"—in effect, you have chosen to hear from us. 

**HealthLINKs**   
If you have signed up to receive E-mail alerts about new HealthLINKs as they become available, you may later wish to change the subscription settings—for example, you want to add "women's health" to the list of categories in which you receive notification. There are three ways you can do this:   

If you should **later change your mind** about receiving information from Yale-New Haven Hospital, please let us know. (This does not cover information related to a hospital admission or a continuing patient relationship.) You can contact us through:   

**Please be very specific** about your wishes. For example, "I no longer wish to receive the hospital's annual report, but I wish to continue receiving _"Advancing Care._ " 

**If you no longer wish to receive** _any_ nonclinical mail, please let us know by sending us a statement such as, "Please remove my name from your mailing lists and consider me a Do Not Contact." Unless you have sent this request in writing, we will confirm requests such as this by return mail. 

* * *

**How secure is the information we have collected about you?** **  
** Most of our interactions with those who visit this site do not involve overly sensitive information. You have already read how we handle information and the cautions we suggest about information transmitted by E-mail. In some cases, however, we have elected to provide an extra level of security. 

At present, information you provide in [Appointments Online](https://createssl.med.yale.edu/ynhh_appoint/appoint_request.lasso) and on the maternity [pre-admission form](https://www.ynhh.org/secure_forms/maternity.html) is protected by [Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)](http://home.netscape.com/security/techbriefs/ssl.html) software, which encrypts the information you input. 

* * *

**Children** **  
** Federal Trade Commission rules prohibit us from collecting any identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without parental permission. We abide by those rules, and so we always request that information on this site of interest to children be requested by their parents or guardians. 

* * *

**More about privacy on the Web** **  
** Yale-New Haven Hospital's Web site operates in compliance with the principles established by the [Health on the Net Foundation](http://www.hon.ch/HONcode/Conduct.html). 

In addition, the Federal Trade Commission provides useful information about online privacy on its Web site, [Site Seeing on the Internet](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html). 

* * *

**Questions?  
**Questions about this site's information gathering and privacy practices can be addressed to the [site editor](http://www.ynhh.org/comments.html). 

Last revised: March 11, 2004 (ps)

Home page URL: http://www.ynhh.org

All information is intended for your general knowledge and is not a substitute for medical advice or treatment for specific medical conditions. You should seek prompt medical care for any specific health issues and consult your physician before starting a new fitness regimen.
